gopher.co.nz 2016-03-14

# Gopher Privacy Policy

Gopher.co.nz is owned and operated by Gopher Limited.

In this Privacy Policy, references to “we” or “us” or “our” are references to Gopher Limited and references to “you” or “your” are references to the person accessing the gopher.co.nz service (“Gopher”).

We are committed to protecting your privacy. You can provide us with as much, or as little, personal information as you feel comfortable with. We use the information we collect to make your experience using Gopher a rewarding one.

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Gopher at www.gopher.co.nz

Moreover, however you use Gopher, our data collection and usage policy allows you to control the personal information you give to us and what we can do with it. In this way your privacy is guaranteed.

We aim to build your trust and confidence in Gopher and we will not hold or use your personal details without your permission.

## What are cookies?

A cookie is a data file that certain web sites write to your computer's hard drive when you visit such sites. Our website uses cookies to log search types and frequency. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to safeguard our information from illegal theft and data mining. We use this data on an anonymous basis and we do not correlate this information with personal data of any user.

Most web site browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our web site, you may not be able to use certain features of Gopher.

## What information do we collect?

We only collect information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you with your permission for example your name, address, email address, and telephone number.

We will also collect data when you request products and services so that we can tailor Gopher to your specific needs.

We also monitor general call centre requests, web site traffic, and user opinions to help us to continually improve Gopher.

## Why do we collect this information?

We collect personal information to provide you with the most relevant service possible. This means in terms of related products and services, and targeted advertising, you only receive information you are interested in.

## How do we use personal information?

We use personal information:

  * To understand more about you so that we can tailor Gopher whenever you access it.
  * To summarise usage behaviour for advertisers and partners, and to describe our service and performance. This is not based on individual behaviour but is generic.
  * To improve Gopher.
  * For other personalised value-added services to which you have specifically subscribed to.

By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set out in this policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the website, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it at all times. Continued use of Gopher will mean that you agree to any such changes.

## What information is collected automatically?

Our web servers automatically collect information about a site user's IP address, browser type, and referrer by reading this information from the user's browser (information provided by every user's browser). This information is collected in a database and used (in an aggregated, anonymous manner) in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our web site.

This information is automatically logged by most web sites.

## How do we protect your information?

The internet is not a secure medium. However, in order to prevent unauthorised access, we use strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information that you have given to us. We use all reasonable endeavours to ensure the security of personal data stored on our system.

All your personal information is password protected and only certain customers who have purchased certain specific products from us have limited password protected access to their own information.

## How do we offer links to third party websites?

This site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for, without limitation, the privacy practices or the accuracy, relevance, copyright compliance, legality, decency of any content or services contained in such websites which are not directly controlled by us. You acknowledge that the search results may contain links to websites and contents that contain offensive or objectionable material. We will not be responsible if the search results reveal such objectionable or offensive content and you release us from all liability in respect of the same. We reserve the right to disable links from third party websites to Gopher.

You should read the terms and conditions of use of any third party website carefully before using that site or proceeding with any online or offline transaction with that third party. Your correspondence or business dealings with, or participation in the promotions of, third parties found on or through Gopher, including payment and delivery of related goods or services, and any other terms, conditions, warranties or representations associated with such dealings (including any implied terms) are solely between you and such third parties.

The inclusion of a link to a third party’s site does not imply endorsement by us of the third party, its site, or any goods, services, information or content featured on or available from that site. We exclude its liability for inter alia:

  * The failure of a third party site to comply with applicable laws or regulations from time to time
  * Any goods, services or content you acquire or access on a third party site
  * Any damage, loss, cost or expense arising from: any link to or from a third party site on Gopher, any third party content on Gopher, any third party content on Gopher or your use of a third party site.

We do not give any warranties or representations as to the security of any information you might be requested to give to any third party, and you irrevocably waive any claim against us with respect to such sites and third party content.

## What choice do we offer in relation to the collection, use and distribution of personal information?

When you register, or when you give us your personal details while using Gopher, you acknowledge and accept that your information may be used for marketing activities, or to receive additional offers and information from us and/or third parties. This is called “permission marketing”.

## Do we share information?

We will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any person or company except where you have given us permission to do so, or if the law requires it, or where in good faith we believe such action is necessary to fulfil the service.

## Privacy Policy – Email

Gopher and its employees respect the privacy needs of their clients and the recipients of any emails sent and received. They do not share with third parties any information about any client or individual and they respect all information contained in their email software and related delivery engines as being confidential.

Gopher will not sell, rent, loan or allow external access to a client's email contact list. Nor will they use their client's email contact lists for any purpose other than those agreed to in writing.

Maintaining the privacy of their client's email contact list information is of paramount importance to Gopher as it fosters confidence, goodwill and good relationships with their clients and their client's customers who receive emails from Gopher.

## What happens if we sell Gopher?

If this business is sold or integrated with another business your details may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and their advisers and will be passed on to the new owners of the business.

## In summary

We want to make your Gopher experience a good one. Your privacy is important. We want you to feel happy about the information you are giving us and to be able to retain control over the way it is used.
